もし　お女中
どうなされた？
You there, maiden.
What's the matter?
うぅ…。
うわぁ～！！　ひぃ！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
What's wrong, mister?
どうなすったい？　お客さん。
I-It appeared!
で…　出やがったんだ。
What appeared?
出たって何が？
A highwayman? A slasher wanting
to try out their new sword?
追いはぎかい？
辻斬りかい？
There have been so many
disturbances lately.
近頃は物騒だからね。
No.
そうじゃねえんだよ。
I-It was a... It's a faceless...
の…　のっぺらぼうが！
What? Faceless?
のっぺらぼう？
ソイツは…。
You mean...
Faceless like this?
（ヤマト）こんな顔かね？
（ナルト）ひゃあ～！！
アハハハハ！　ごめん　ごめん
それは　僕の木遁分身だ。
Sorry, sorry.
That's my Wood Clone.
ヤマト隊長　懲りすぎだってばよ。
Captain Yamato, that's going too far.
うわぁ～！！
それにしても　ナルトは怖がりだな。
Still, Naruto.
You're such a scaredy cat.
Captain Yamato,
your face is bad for my heart.
ヤマト隊長の顔が
いちばん心臓に悪い。
Don't be so upset, Naruto.
（ヤマト）そうむくれるな　ナルト。
The fog's so thick,
there's nothing else to do.
こう霧がひどくては
他にすることもないしね。
Yeah, but a grown man like you
telling ghost stories?
だからって　いい大人が怪談なんて
どうかしてると思うな　俺。
Something’s wrong with you!
You're so easy to scare.
That's why.
（アオバ）お前が怖がりすぎなんだって
だから。
俺は　その話
ちっとも怖くなんかねえってばよ。
Stories like that don't
scare me one bit.
ほう　そういうことなら
とっておきの話をしよう。
Okay then,
I'll tell you the best one yet.
I've heard that it appears
on days like this.
こんな日には　あれが出るって
聞いたことがあるんだ。
Huh? "It"?
あれ？
It appears, led in by black crows that
guide the souls of dead men.
（ヤマト）それは　死者の魂を導く
カラスの先導で現れる。
マストに灯した巨大な鬼火が
そいつの証し。
A giant friar's lantern
that lights the mast
confirms its presence.
深い深い霧は　死者の魂。
The thick, thick fog embodies
the souls of dead people.
When you encounter it,
出会ったが最後
死者の国への船旅が始まる。
the final journey to
the land of the dead begins.
それが　幽霊船だ。
That is...
the ghost ship.
Souls of dead people?
死者の魂？
あっ　まさか　この霧。
D-Don't tell me this fog...
Yes. The ghost ship appears
out of fog like this.
そう　こんな霧の中から
幽霊船が現れるのさ。
な～んてね
幽霊船なんて古い迷信さ。
Just kidding. A ghost ship is
just an old superstition.
ヘヘ　だよな
そんなのいるわけねえもんな。
I thought so.
Of course, there's no such thing.
I didn't believe you for a second.
俺ってば
ちっとも信じてなかったってばよ。
へえ　そうは見えなかったけどね。
You could've fooled me.
風が動いた。
The wind just picked up.
何なんだ？
What was that?!
あっ！
これは…。
This is...
幽霊船！？
A ghost ship?!
そんな　まさか…。
No way. It can’t be!
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
The Cursed Ghost Ship
You've got to be kidding!
マジかよ　幽霊船に乗り込むなんて
冗談じゃねえってばよ。
Are you seriously gonna
board a ghost ship?!
Naruto, there's no such thing
as a ghost ship.
ナルト　幽霊船なんてものは
この世に存在しない。
There sure is. Look at that.
あるじゃねえか　あそこに　ほら！
It's exactly how
Captain Yamato described it.
全部　ヤマト隊長の
言ってたとおりだってばよ。
確かに　うさんくさい船だが→
It's definitely
a suspicious-looking ship,
but marine laws dictate that
lost ships must not be left ignored.
航海法で　難破船を→
そのままにしておくわけには
いかないんだ。
早く調査を済ませれば→
The sooner we check it out,
the sooner we can get back
to our boat.
それだけ早く船に
戻れるということだ。
So give it up.
あきらめるんだな。
If that's the case,
こんなことなら　ゲキマユ先生の
つきそいでもしてたほうが→
I should have stayed back
with Bushy Brow Sensei.
まだ　マシだった。
（ガイ）ナルト　ガッツだぞ！
Naruto, it's all about guts!
As long as you have guts,
ghosts or whatever are...
ガッツさえあれば　幽霊だろうと
なんだろうと…。
It's only seasickness.
Get over it with guts.
船酔いぐらい
ガッツで克服しろっての！
Right, Aoba?
なぁ　アオバのおっちゃん…。
W-Wait a minute.
ちょっと待って…！
Hey Aoba... Captain Yamato...
お～い　おっちゃん　ヤマト隊長。
Man, I'm so busy, busy, busy.
（ヒシャク）ああ　忙しい　忙しい！
Hey...
なぁ。
My face isn't the floor. Hey.
俺の顔は床じゃねえぞ　こら！
忙しい　忙しい！
So busy, so busy.
Wow.
待てよ！
Hey, wait!
So busy, so busy!
忙しい　忙しい！
H-Hey!
おいって！　ホント忙しいヤツだな。
He really is a busy guy.
へぇ　それで船を操るのか。
Oh... So that's how you
operate the ship.
Hey, you've really made
good use of this brush.
おっ　何だ　ずいぶん
使い込んだブラシだったんだな。
Don't touch it!
触るなよ！
The captain gave it to me.
It's very precious to me.
それはな　船長からもらった
大切なものなんだ！
O-Okay, I get it.
わ…　わかったよ。
でも　オメエ　ガキのくせに
メチャクチャ働き者なんだな。
For a young kid,
you really work hard.
１人じゃ大変だろ？
Isn't it hard all by yourself?
よっしゃ　俺も手伝うってばよ！
All right! I'll help you!
１人より２人！
Two is better than one.
In fact, a bunch of us will finish
much faster than just two!
２人より大勢でやったほうが
早く終わるってもんだ。
After all, I don't think I'll get to talk
to you unless you finish your work.
それに　オメエの
仕事が終わんねえと→
話を聞いて
もらえそうにないからな。
どりゃ～っ！
Boy, am I tired.
あ～　疲れた。
Say brother...
お兄ちゃん。
あ？　俺は　ナルトってんだ。
Huh? My name's Naruto.
ナルト　俺　ヒシャク。
Naruto... I'm Hishaku.
おう　よろしくな！
Nice to meet you.
You're a ninja, Naruto?
Are you strong?
ナルトは　忍者だったんだな。
強いのか？
Of course, I'm strong.
ヘヘン　あったりめえよ！
I'm aiming to become the Hokage.
これでも火影を
目指してるんだぜ。
The Hokage?
火影？
ああ。
Yup! The strongest and
most important ninja in the village.
里でいちばん強くて
偉い忍ってことだ。
Is that all?
なんだ　それなら火影ってのより
船長のほうがすごいよ。
Well, my captain is even greater
than your Hokage.
W-What?!
なっ　なに！？
The captain is strong and
not just important.
船長は
強くて偉いだけじゃなくって→
He's kind and considerate of others.
優しくて仲間思いなんだ。
俺も　いつか船長になるんだ！
I'm gonna become
a captain too one day!
H-Hold it!
いや　ちょ　ちょっと待て！
My Hokage is strong and
important and kind,
火影は　強くて　偉くて　優しくて
仲間思いだけじゃなくって→
and not just considerate,
but generous.
気前がよくって　え～と
それから　あ～　それから。
And... and...
い～や　船長！
No, my captain is!
火影！
船長！
The Hokage!
The captain!
火影だ！
船長！
The captain!
ハハッ！
アハハ！
お互い目指してるものが
あるんだな。
So we both have something
we're aiming for.
うん。
そうだ　あれ教えてくれよ。
By the way, teach me that thing.
あれ？
That thing?
The way you tapped the brush earlier.
ほら　さっきのブラシの
タンタンって叩くヤツ。
なかなか　かっこよかったぜ。
That was cool.
あれは船長に教わったんだ。
The captain taught it to me.
このブラシも
船長からもらったんだよ。
The captain gave me
this brush too.
ふ～ん。
Can we join in your conversation?
（ヤマト）僕らも　話に
まぜてもらっていいかな？
あちこち回ったけど→
I looked around,
but it's just an ordinary ship
on the inside, Captain Yamato.
中は　ごく普通の船だったぜ
ヤマト隊長。
It's not a ghost ship.
やっぱ
幽霊船じゃないんじゃねえの？
アハハ　幽霊船だって
そんなの迷信に決まってるよ。
A ghost ship?
That's just a superstition.
But...
だけど　あれってば
人魂じゃなかったのか？
Isn't that made up of human souls?
マストの炎？
あれは船乗りの間じゃ→
You mean the glow on the mast?
Well, among sailors, it's supposed
to be a sign of good luck.
幸運のしるしって
言われているものでさ。
That's just static electricity discharging.
静電気が
光って見えてるだけだよ。
せ　静電気？
S-Static electricity?
Then what about the crows on the mast?
じゃあ　マストのカラスは？
普通　カラスなんて海にいねえぞ。
You don't normally find crows
on the ocean.
あれは　カラスじゃないよ。
Those aren't crows.
They're just seabirds taking a rest.
羽を休めている海鳥が
煙突のススで汚れただけ。
They’re dirty from the ash coming
from the smokestack.
マジかよ。
Really?
さあ　幽霊船の話は
おいておくとして→
Putting aside talk about a ghost ship,
僕たちも　船の中を
調べさせてもらったが→
we took the liberty of checking
the inside of this ship too.
この船には　キミ以外の乗組員が
いないようだね。
It seems there are no other sailors
on board besides you.
他の乗組員は
どうしたんだい？
What happened to them?
このクラスの船となると→
A ship this class requires
quite a few deckhands.
それなりの人数が
必要なはずだが。
That's right.
そういや
ブラシの船長もいねえな。
Where's the captain who
gave you the brush?
うん　いたよ　仲間たちが。
Yeah.
I used to have shipmates.
何かあったようだね。
I presume something happened.
海には　幽霊船なんて
バカな迷信なんかよりも→
Under the sea,
lurks something
even more terrifying
よっぽど恐ろしいものが
潜んでいるんだ。
than some stupid superstition
about a ghost ship.
It’s here!
アイツだ！
アイツ？
It?
ああ　そうだ
伝説の海のバケモノ　ムクロオオガニだよ！
Oh yes.
The legendary sea monster,
the Skeleton Crab!
カニ？
違う！　ただのカニなんかじゃない！
Crab?
It's not an ordinary crab!
小さな島ぐらいある
大きなヤツなんだ！
It's huge, the size of a small island.
甲羅は頑丈だし
でっかいハサミに囚われたら最後→
Its shell is rock hard
and if you get caught between
its pinchers, it's over.
It can pulverize anything!
どんなものでも
粉々にされちゃう！
And the barnacles that are
attached on the shell
それに　甲羅に寄生したフジツボは
生きたまま　人を食らうんだ。
devour humans alive!
船長も　他のみんなも
みんな　みんな…　アイツに。
The captain and the rest of
the crew...
They were all killed by it.
ナルト！　忍って強いんだろ？
Naruto! Ninja are strong, right?
Please destroy it and avenge
the captain and the others!
アイツのことやっつけて
船長たちの敵をとってくれよ！
うわっ！
隊長！
あぁ～っ！
Captain!
Oh no...
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
♪～
ヤマト隊長！
That thing’s gonna...
あぁ…　アイツが　また！
Leave it to me, Hishaku!
心配すんな　ヒシャク！
俺が　アイツをぶっ飛ばしてやる！
I'll crush that thing!
Aoba, take Hishaku back to
the ship with you!
アオバのおっちゃん！
ヒシャクと一緒に　船に戻って→
And let everyone know about this.
みんなに　このことを
知らせてくれってばよ！
But...
しかし…。
We don't have time to
stand around and think!
迷ってるヒマなんかねえよ！
One of us has to save Captain Yamato
and stop that monster crab,
ヤマト隊長を助けて
バケモンガニをとめる役か→
or notify the others on the ship.
船の仲間に
このことを知らせる役か→
Each of us has to do one task.
どっちかを
２人がやんなきゃなんねえ！
You probably can explain things
to the others
俺よか　アオバのおっちゃんのほうが
冷静に伝えられるだろ！
more calmly than me, Aoba.
He's become so reliable.
フンッ　頼もしくなったものだ。
Okay, I'll take on that job.
わかった！　その役は
俺が引き受けよう！
Naruto, aren't you scared?
ナルト…　怖くないの？
あんな　バケモノ相手にするなんて！
How can you take on that monster?
I told you.
言っただろ！
俺は　火影を目指してんだ！
I'm aiming to become
the Hokage some day.
If it's for my comrades,
I'm not afraid of anything.
仲間のためなら
ちっとも怖くなんてねえってばよ。
For your comrades...
仲間のため…。
Hishaku... You're still young.
((ヒシャク！　お前は　まだ幼い。
せめて　お前だけでも
助かってくれ！
You must live.
I'm scared, Captain!
怖いよ　船長…。
Please stay with me, Captain.
船長も一緒に。
I've had this from the time
I joined this ship.
こいつは　俺が　この船に
乗り込んだときからのつきあいだ。
さぁ　こいつを持っててくれ。
Take this.
えっ！？
Those worn-down bristles
carry my soul in them.
この　すり減ったブラシが
俺の魂だ。
If you take it,
I'll know it's in good hands.
お前が持っててくれれば
俺も安心なんだよ。
Captain!
船長…。
I still have work to do.
俺には　まだ仕事が残ってる。
It's my job to stay with
my ship until the end,
俺を信じて　ついてきてくれた
仲間のためにも→
for the sake of my comrades who
believed in me and stayed with me.
船の最後を見届けるっていう
仕事がな。
That's the duty of a ship's captain.
(それが船長ってもんだ))
Just you wait.
I'll get revenge for you!
待ってろよ　俺が　オメエの敵
とってきてやっからな！
That's Naruto Uzumaki,
あれが木ノ葉の里を救った英雄
うずまきナルトだ。
the hero who saved
the Hidden Leaf Village.
Naruto Uzumaki.
うずまきナルト…。
Let's get back to our ship.
さぁ行こう　俺たちの船に。
You good-for-nothing...
Going around threatening everyone!
この野郎　脅かしやがって！
If you're not a ghost,
then you don't scare me one bit!
お化けじゃなけりゃ→
お前なんかちっとも
怖くねえんだよ！
Rasengan!
螺旋丸！
クソッ　さすがバケモンガニ
甲羅は硬ぇってばよ。
Damn! That monster crab has
a hard shell, all right!
This thing... It's not only strong,
but it's fast too.
コイツ　頑丈なだけじゃねえ。
意外に素早いぞ。
Aoba, our ship is swaying badly.
What's going on?
アオバ　俺も船も大揺れだ。
いったい　どうした？
We have to get out of
this area immediately.
急いで　この海域から
脱出しなければなりません。
Naruto is buying us
some time right now.
今　ナルトがその時間を
稼いでくれているんです。
Captain... Grant me the courage.
船長　俺に勇気を！
Captain Yamato!
ヤマト隊長！
I can't do anything big to settle this.
《大技で勝負ってわけには
いかねえか》
I have to save Captain Yamato quickly!
早くヤマト隊長を助けねえと。
Damn it.
野郎！
This is bad!
やべぇ！
Everyone, please lend me
your strength!
みんな　力を貸して！
♪～
They got it.
しめた！　ヒシャクがやったのか？
助かった。
I wonder if Hishaku did it.
That helped!
Captain Yamato!
ヤマト隊長！
油断した。
I was careless.
To get caught by something like this...
I'm embarrassed.
こんなのに捕まるとは　面目ない。
いいってばよ。
Don't worry about it.
あっ！
Hey, Naruto!
お～い　ナルト！
Captain Yamato, now!
ヤマト隊長　今だ。
That shell is unbelievably hard.
ヤツの甲羅は
とてつもなく硬ぇんだ。
I see. So I should aim for the soft area.
なるほど。　やわらかいところを
狙おうっていうんだね。
Wood Style Jutsu!
木遁の術！
Now, Naruto!
今だ　ナルト！
I know!
わかってるってばよ！
Hishaku, lend me some
of your courage!
ヒシャク　おめえの勇気を貸してくれ。
Gotcha.
うん。
Prepare yourself, you monster crab!
覚悟しやがれ　バケモンガニ！
Rasengan!
螺旋丸！
You did it, Naruto.
やったな　ナルト。
Yeah. Thanks to Hishaku.
ああ　ヒシャクのおかげだってばよ。
I guess you realized
your dream before I did.
俺より先に
夢　叶えちまったみてえだな。
I’ve only known you for
a short while,
ちょっとの間だったけどよ
おめえってば→
but you're one hell of a captain,
kind of like the Hokage.
火影にも負けねえ
立派な船長だったぜ。
Thank you, Naruto.
ありがとう　ナルト。
俺　ずっと後悔してたんだ。
I always felt regret
that I wasn't able to fight
with the others back then.
あのとき　みんなと一緒に
戦えなかったことを。
But you avenged everyone
だから　ナルトが
みんなの敵をとってくれて→
and the heaviness in
my heart is gone.
胸のつかえが取れた気分だよ。
Aw, come on.
よせよ！　バケモンガニを倒せたのは
ヒシャクのおかげだ。
I was able to destroy that
monster crab all because of you.
And you’re one of our comrades now.
それに　お前ももう
俺たちの仲間だしな。
Yeah, you’re right!
うん　そうだね。
ん？
But it’s time to say goodbye, Naruto.
でも　もう　さよならだ　ナルト。
H-Hey, what's going on?
お　おい　どうなってんだ？
Hey, where'd you go?
おい　どこ行ったんだってばよ？
Hishaku! No one's blaming you!
ヒシャク！
誰も　おめえを責めたりしねえよ。
What a problem.
You’re too honorable!
変に責任感が強いから
困ったもんだ。
You couldn’t rest in peace,
so we couldn’t either!
おめえが成仏しねえから→
俺たちまで
成仏できねえんじゃねえか。
I'm sorry, everyone.
ごめんね　みんな。
You don't need to apologize.
なあに　謝ることはないさ。
We felt so relieved when
that damn crab got hit directly!
あのカニ野郎に
体当たりをかましたときにゃ→
俺たちも　スカッとしたぜ。
– Yeah, yeah!
そのだ　そうだ！
そのとおり！
All right, how about we liven
things up with the usual?
よし　景気づけに
いつものやつをやるぞ　みんな！
– Right!
お～！
さよなら　ナルト！
Goodbye, Naruto!
– Take care!
（みんな）達者でな！
Right. Hishaku, take care of yourself!
ああ　ヒシャク　元気でな！
えっ…　ウソだろう？
No way...
うわぁ～！　幽霊船だ！
A ghost ship!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokyuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
dance dance dance to you
just just just to you
akai itode tsunagacchattenda
We're connected by the Red String of Fate
dareka ga dareka wo damashite achichi
Somebody is doing something
burning hot by deceiving somebody
sonna de iinoka?
Are you OK with that?
ore wa chigauze baka ni sunjanee
I'm not like them. You don't know the first thing about me
kitanai kirei giragira no sora
The dirty, beautiful sky glitters
antanimo mieterunokai?
Can you see it too?
hageshiku aishi aisareta koto wa arunokai?
Have you ever loved, and been loved, passionately?
ore to anta no kizuna wa dounatterundai?
What's become of our bond?
c'mon!
haato dokyun de bachibachi sunzen
My heart is thumping and about to explode
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! aini mudawanee!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Love is it!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Next Episode
The rudder doesn’t work at all! This is some storm!
What’s going to happen if we drift on this current?
It seems like we’ll be okay!
If we remain on this current, we’ll still be on course.
All right! We’ll head straight to the Land of Lightning!
Wait Naruto, something’s heading this way!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Battleship Island!"
Battleship Island!
It’s an attack! Wait, what is that?